<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<timedtext>
    <text d="5824" t="5914">
        Hi everyone. In this video, we will get to know how to add multiple languages for closed captions.
    </text>
    <text d="3918" t="12600">
        Thanks to that, viewers can toggle between languages based on their choice.
    </text>
    <text d="5407" t="18753">
        To be more precise, I will work with the presentation about volcanoes that I have created here.
    </text>
    <text d="6037" t="24509">
        Suppose that I want to add closed captions to that slide to help viewers easily follow its content.
    </text>
    <text d="2481" t="31112">
        The first step is adding closed captions.
    </text>
    <text d="3989" t="34196">
        To do that, you can click the Insert tab and select Closed Caption.
    </text>
    <text d="6538" t="38735">
        Alternatively, I prefer clicking the Insert Caption button which has the same function in the Timeline pane.
    </text>
    <text d="3500" t="46505">
        After that, one CC node is inserted at the Playhead position.
    </text>
    <text d="4857" t="50425">
        On the Canvas, this is a closed caption editor that allows you to type the caption.
    </text>
    <text d="5960" t="56748">
        Furthermore, it’s possible to add as many closed captions as you want or import them from a caption file.
    </text>
    <text d="4175" t="63152">
        Please refer to our video Working with Closed Captions for more details.
    </text>
    <text d="5320" t="67772">
        After adding a closed caption, its start time and duration by default may be inappropriate.
    </text>
    <text d="6397" t="73512">
        The first and easiest way to change them is dragging the CC node or its ends along the timeline ruler.
    </text>
    <text d="5180" t="81512">
        Or you can also set values from the Timing section in the Size &amp; Properties tab.
    </text>
    <text d="5213" t="87255">
        You should display each CC line for adequate time so that your viewers can read it comfortably
    </text>
    <text d="4806" t="93070">
        Next, you will come to the second step: adding more languages to a closed caption.
    </text>
    <text d="4900" t="98416">
        You can either click the arrow next to the Closed Caption button, and select Multiple Languages.
    </text>
    <text d="3859" t="103756">
        Or, in the Properties pane of the CC, click this icon.
    </text>
    <text d="3061" t="109911">
        You will see the Edit Language dialog appears like this.
    </text>
    <text d="5061" t="113472">
        In the Language section, the default language of the closed captions is the project language.
    </text>
    <text d="3134" t="118853">
        In my presentation, English is the default language.
    </text>
    <text d="4320" t="122616">
        Now, I will add one more language, for example, the Russian language.
    </text>
    <text d="2377" t="127396">
        To do that, you click the plus button here.
    </text>
    <text d="4310" t="132181">
        Then click the drop-down arrow and choose the Russian language from the list.
    </text>
    <text d="1358" t="139024">
        Click OK to apply.
    </text>
    <text d="5047" t="141948">
        Click here if you want the new language to be the default language displaying in closed captions.
    </text>
    <text d="3479" t="147586">
        Or click here to delete a language that you no longer need.
    </text>
    <text d="4200" t="151875">
        Here, the Caption Editor section is a place to edit further language.
    </text>
    <text d="5961" t="156755">
        Just select Show Original check box to simultaneously show both default language and a new language.
    </text>
    <text d="3660" t="163156">
        This allows you to see exactly which CC line you are working with.
    </text>
    <text d="3108" t="167970">
        Edit the new language by typing or pasting text here.
    </text>
    <text d="5604" t="172340">
        In case you want to create a bilingual closed caption that combines the original language and the new one,
    </text>
    <text d="2440" t="178224">
        the Insert Original button is here to help.
    </text>
    <text d="3841" t="181209">
        Choose the position you want to insert, then click this button.
    </text>
    <text d="3000" t="185987">
        However, this CC line may be too long.
    </text>
    <text d="5541" t="189227">
        In this case, you should break it into several lines, which helps viewers read it comfortably.
    </text>
    <text d="2385" t="195368">
        Click Add Line Break or press ENTER key.
    </text>
    <text d="3458" t="199578">
        A tag here is inserted to break the line at this position.
    </text>
    <text d="2370" t="203796">
        After all, click Close to apply.
    </text>
    <text d="5341" t="208216">
        To see multiple languages in the CC editor, simply go to the General section of the Properties pane
    </text>
    <text d="3820" t="214017">
        Click the drop-down arrow, and choose the language you want to preview.
    </text>
    <text d="7134" t="218537">
        After that, you are also able to edit the text of the new language in the CC editor as the same as the default language.
    </text>
    <text d="5362" t="226391">
        Edit the text or the fill style of the closed captions using commands and options available...
    </text>
    <text d="5004" t="231753">
        ...in the Home tab, Format tab, or the Properties pane.
    </text>
    <text d="3500" t="238445">
        So, by how viewers can switch to the language of their choice?
    </text>
    <text d="1261" t="242218">
        It’s so simple
    </text>
    <text d="8220" t="243939">
        ActivePresenter gives viewers control over showing or hiding CC, or togging CC language by enabling the CC button in the player.
    </text>
    <text d="5220" t="252699">
        To enable the CC button, click the Export tab first, select Player Settings.
    </text>
    <text d="3120" t="259359">
        The Player Settings window will pop up and show further settings.
    </text>
    <text d="4520" t="263160">
        In the General tab, select the CC Button check box in the Toolbar section.
    </text>
    <text d="5820" t="268500">
        Once the CC Button check box is selected, ActivePresenter automatically adds a CC button to the player,
    </text>
    <text d="3261" t="274640">
        which allows viewers to toggle the closed caption as they wish.
    </text>
    <text d="3685" t="278460">
        After that, don’t forget to click OK to save changes.
    </text>
    <text d="1663" t="282617">
        So, hope it will help.
    </text>
    <text d="1001" t="284874">
        Thanks for watching.
    </text>
</timedtext>